In the last lecture I showed you how to add interceptors. Now sometimes, you don't want to intercept
Son derste ilgi alan belirleyicilerinin nasl ekleneceini gsterdim imdi bazen
the request but you want to set up some global configuration.
istei kesmek istemiyorsunuz, ancak baz genel yaplandrma kurmak istiyorsunuz.
Let's say the URL you are sending the requests to in your application is always the same,
Diyelim ki, istekleri gnderiyorsunuz ve bavurunuz daima ayn.
so it's always jsonplaceholder.typeicode in our case here and then slash something.
Dolaysyla her zaman bir yer veya eski tip II kod bizim durumumuzda ve daha sonra bir ey kesmek.
So that starting part is always the same
Bylece balang ksm daima ayndr.
so it would be nice if we could cut it out here and just send the request to get posts and automatically
Peki burada kesip, mesajlar almak iin istei yollayabilirsek ne gzel olurdu
append this to some comments starting URL.
ve l baladnda otomatik olarak rak olurdu.
Turns out we can do that in the index.js file which is a good place because it runs first, it starts
dizinde sonbahar olarak iyi bir yer olduu iin bunu yapabileceiz. nce almaya balyor.
to react app,
Bir sonraki
We can use axios and there access to defaults object to set up defaults which are true for all requests
X yln ve rneklerini, varsaylan olarak, gnderilen tm istekler iin varsaylanlar ayarlamak
which are being sent. And there we can define a baseURL and this URL will now be used, well
iin kullanabiliriz ve orada bir l baznda bir l baznda bir l baznda bir
as the names suggests, as a baseURL to which the other paths are then simply appended.
l baznda l ismini bulabiliriz POV'lerinizin basite eklendii L'nizin temelini oluturun.
Now with that set up here, whoops set by the way important should be baseURL with capital characters
imdi burada ayarladklarmz, nemli olmas gerekeni belirledik. Eurail, burada Ural gvdesi
here for the URL, casing is important here.
iin bakent karakterleriyle burada nemli.
Now we already removed it from get all posts here in the block container,
imdi, buradaki tm yaynlar blok konteynerinden almak iin kaldrdk.
now in new post, we can also get rid of it when posting data
imdi, yeni yaz gnderirken veri gnderirken hepsinden kurtulabiliriz.
and in the full post, there we have two places, one where we get to single post and one where we delete
Ve tam yaz orada tek bir yaz almak iin bir tane ve tek bir yazy silmek zere iki yer
the single post. So we can get rid of that starting URL everywhere and if we go back to the app, you
var, bylece her yerden balayarak kurtulmaktan kurtulabiliriz ve eer uygulamanza geri dndmzde yine de
see it still loads, it still works,
onu yklediini grrsnz hala alyor.
everything still works fine here because we didn't really change the way we sent requests but we
Her ey hala iyi iliyor burada nk istek gnderdiimiz ekli gerekten deitirmedik ama bu
made it a bit easier for us because of that global configuration.
genel yaplandrma yznden bunu biraz daha kolay hale getirdik.
Now you're also not limited to just setting the baseURL here,
Artk yalnzca L'nizi buraya eklemeyle snrl deilsiniz.
you can also access defaults headers and there set a common header, so on that common object of authorization,
bir nesnesinde veya yalnzca tm talep trleri iin belirlenmi olan genel stbilgiler zerinde ortak bir balk ayarlayabilirsiniz
common headers are simply the general headers which are set for all types of requests, and there you could
ve orada bir veya daha fazlas varsa bunlar belirte olarak ayarlayabilirsiniz yani.
set this to your auth token if you had one or whatever that is.
Varsaylan balklara da eriebilirsiniz ve genel ortak balklarn ortak
You can also set headers just for specific request types, like for post requests only where you maybe
Ayrca, post istekleri gibi yalnzca belirli istek trlerine ynelik balklar da ayarlayabilirsiniz; buna, ihtiyacnz
want to set the content type you're sending to application.json, which you don't need to, that's the
olmayan bavuru Chaisson'a gndermek istediiniz ierik trn ayarlamak istediiniz varsaylan koultur, bunun da
default anyways, just to show this.
sadece varsaylan gstermeniz yeterlidir.
So now if you do this, if you go back to the application and you inspect the request which was sent, you
imdi bunu uygulamanza geri dnerseniz ve gnderilen istei incelerseniz,
will see that under headers, we've got the authorization auth token
balklarn altnda tekliflerin otomatik olarak aldn greceksiniz.
and for a post request here, if we do that, you will see that there if we inspect the request configuration
Ve bir mesaj talebi iin, istei konfigrasyonunu incelersek, kapal resepsiyon stbilgisi ve
we got the authorization header and Content-Type
erik Tr'n bulduumuzu greceksin.
application.json.
Uygulama Jason.
So that's another cool feature of axios,
Bu da, bir baka gzel zellik.
setting a default configuration which will be used application wide, super awesome,
Uygulama geni sper harika olacak ekilde kullanlacak bir varsaylan yaplandrmann ayarlanmas.
helps you to optimize your code quite a lot.
Kodunuzu ok fazla optimize etmenize yardmc olur.